As we are looking at the query review hook
쿼리 검토 훅을 보고 있는 동안
a moment ago, we got a brief look at the Claude code SDK.
잠시 전에 Claude 코드 SDK를 간략하게 살펴보았습니다.
The SDK allows you to use Claude code programmatically.
SDK를 사용하면 프로그래밍 방식으로 Claude 코드를 사용할 수 있습니다.
You can use the SDK via the CLI, TypeScript
CLI, TypeScript
library or Python library. This is the exact
라이브러리 또는 Python 라이브러리를 통해 SDK를 사용할 수 있습니다. 이것은 정확히
same Claude code that you will already use at the terminal. It
터미널에서 이미 사용하고 있는 Claude 코드와 동일합니다.
has all the same tools and will use them to complete a given
모든 동일한 도구를 가지고 있으며 이를 사용하여 주어진
task. The SDK is most useful
작업을 완료할 것입니다. SDK는 가장 유용합니다
as part of a larger pipeline or tool as we saw
방금 보았듯이 더 큰 파이프라인 또는 도구의 일부로
in that hook a moment to go. You can easily wiring
훅에서요. 쉽게 연결할 수 있습니다
Claude Code as part of a larger process to add
더 큰 프로세스의 일부로 Claude 코드를
in a bunch of intelligence to some given workflow. I'd
더 많은 지능을 추가하기 위해. 저는
like to give you a quick demonstration of the TypeScript
TypeScript SDK에 대한 간단한 시연을 보여드리고 싶습니다.
SDK in particular by adding it into our existing
특히 기존 프로젝트에 추가하여
project. Back inside of my editor, I'm
내 편집기 안으로 돌아가서
going to find the SDK.ts file inside of the root
루트 프로젝트 디렉토리의 SDK.ts 파일을 찾을 것입니다. 여기 안에서 저는
project directory. Inside of here, I put together just
SDK를 시작하는 데 도움이 될 약간의 코드를 준비했습니다. 저는
a little bit of code to get us started with the SDK. I'm
상단의 프롬프트를 업데이트하고 Claude에게
going to update the prompt at the top and ask Claude to
SRC
look for duplicate queries inside the SRC
queries 디렉토리에서 중복 쿼리를 찾도록 요청할 것입니다.
queries directory. Then I'm going to save this file and
그런 다음 이 파일을 저장하고
to run it, I'll open up my terminal and execute NPMRun
실행하려면 터미널을 열고 NPMRun을 실행합니다.
SDK. Now, this is not a built-in
SDK. 이제 이것은 내장된 것이 아닙니다.
command or anything like that just so you know, but in the scenes, it just executes
명령어나 그런 것은 아닙니다. 내부적으로는 그냥 실행됩니다.
this file as a normal TypeScript file. I just put
이 파일을 일반 TypeScript 파일로 사용합니다. 저는 단지
together this little shortcut for us to make running a TypeScript file
이 작은 바로 가기를 사용하여 TypeScript 파일을 실행하기 쉽게 만들었습니다.
a little bit easier. When we run this, we'll see the raw
이것을 실행하면 원시 대화를 볼 수 있습니다.
conversation between our local copy of Claude Code and
Claude 코드의 로컬 복사본과
the Claude Language model, message by message. Eventually,
Claude 언어 모델 간의 메시지별 대화입니다. 결국
we'll get kicked back to the command line. The very last message
명령줄로 돌아올 것입니다. 마지막 메시지
printed out will contain the final response from Claude.
출력된 내용은 Claude의 최종 응답을 포함합니다.
Now there is a little bit of a gotcha around the SDK.
SDK에 약간의 함정이 있습니다.
And that is that by default, it only has read abilities.
즉, 기본적으로 읽기 권한만 있습니다.
So in other words, it can only read files, directories,
다른 말로 하면 파일을 읽거나 디렉토리를 읽을 수 있습니다.
do grep operations, and so on. It does not
grep 작업을 수행하고 기타 등등.
have the ability to write or edit or create and
쓰기, 편집 또는 생성 권한은 없습니다.
so on files. To give it right permissions,
등등 파일을. 쓰기 권한을 부여하려면
you can either manually add in right permissions to the query
쿼리에 쓰기 권한을 수동으로 추가하거나
call right here, or alternatively, you can add in
이곳의 호출, 또는 대안으로
some permission settings to your settings file
점멸 Claude 디렉토리에 있는 설정 파일에
inside of your dot-Claude directory. Let me show you how
일부 권한 설정을 추가할 수 있습니다. 제가 어떻게 하는지 보여드리겠습니다.
we can allow the SDK to use the edit tool
이 프로젝트 내에서 SDK가 편집 도구를 사용하도록 허용합니다.
within this project. I'm going to find the prompt argument
여기 있는 프롬프트 인수를 찾을 것입니다.
right here. Right after it, I'll add in options, put
그 바로 뒤에 옵션을 추가하고
in an object, allow tools, that'll
도구 허용 개체를 넣을 것입니다.
be an array, and I'll put in edit. I'm
그것은 배열이 될 것이며 저는 편집을 넣을 것입니다. 저는
going to update the prompt at the top and I'll ask it to
상단의 프롬프트를 업데이트하고 그것에게
add a description to the package.json
package.json 파일에 설명을 추가하도록 요청할 것입니다.
file. Now I'm going to save this and
이제 저장하고
run npmrunsdk once again. And
npmrunsdk를 다시 실행합니다. 그리고
then once it is complete, I can open up the
완료되면
package.json file and I will see that it did in fact
package.json 파일을 열면 실제로
add in a description. So now definitely has the ability
설명이 추가되었음을 알 수 있습니다. 그래서 이제 확실히
to edit files. As I mentioned earlier,
파일을 편집할 수 있습니다. 앞에서 언급했듯이
the Claude Code SDK is most useful as
Claude 코드 SDK는 가장 유용합니다.
part of other tools. So I would encourage you to think
다른 도구의 일부로. 따라서 생각해보시기를 권장합니다.
of opportunities to use it in helper commands, scripts,
도우미 명령, 스크립트,
or probably most notably hooks inside of your
또는 아마도 가장 주목할 만한 것은
own projects.
자신의 프로젝트 내의 훅입니다.